{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "1. A rectangular pontoon is 5 m long, 3 m wide and 1.40 m high. The depth of immersion of the pontoon is 0.60 m in seawater. If the centre of gravity is 0.7 m above the bottom of the pontoon, determine the metacentric height. The density for seawater = 1045 kg/m3.",
        "answers": {
          "a": "0.135",
          "b": "0.271",
          "c": "0.543",
          "d": "0.068"
        },
        
        "correctAnswer": "a",
        "difficulty": "beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "2. A uniform body of size 4 m long * 2.5 m wide * 1.5 m deep floats in water. What is the weight of the body if depth of immersion is 1 m ?",
        "answers": {
          "a": "147.1 kN",
          "b": "294.3 kN",
          "c": "73.5 kN",
          "d": "588.6 kN"
        },
       
        "correctAnswer": "a",
        "difficulty": "beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"3. A block of material of specific gravity 0.45 floats in water. Determine the meta-centric height of the block if its size is 3 m * 2 m* 0.8 m.",
        "answers":{
          "a": "0.506 m",
          "b": "0.376 m",
          "c": "1.012 m",
          "d": "0.127 m"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"b",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"4. A solid cylinder of diameter 4.5 has a height of 2.5 metres. Find the meta-centric height of the cylinder when it is floating in water with its axis vertical. The sp. gr. of the cylinder=0.45",
        "answers":{
          "a":"1.9 m",
          "b": "3.8 m",
          "c": "5.7 m",
          "d": "0.95 m"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "5. In case of spherically shaped bodies of uniform mass distribution and completely immersed in fluid and floating, the centre of buoyancy coincides with centre of gravity.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"6. Proper explanation for metacentre is: ",
        "answers":{
          "a":"Point at which line of action of force meets the normal axis of body when it is given angular displacement",
          "b":"Intersection of line passing through new centre of buoyancy and centre of gravity.",
          "c":"point about which body starts oscillating when it is given small angular displacement",
          "d": "All of the mentioned"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"d",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"7. The metacentric height is affected by the change in density.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"8. For a completely immersed body, the metacentric height is always zero.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"b",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"9. Meta centre always lies below the centre of gravity",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"b",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
        },{
          "question":"10. The principle of floatation of bodies is based on the premise of",
          "answers":{
            "a":"Metacentre",
            "b":"Newtons first law",
            "c":"Newtons law of viscosity",
            "d":"None of the mentioned"
          },
          "correctAnswer":"a",
          "difficulty":"beginner"
        }
    
    ]
  }